Asher Shaheen

144-87 41st Ave Flushing, NY 11355 | C: 646-342-5919 | E: <u>ashershaheen@gmail.com</u>

Portfolio | Github

CAREER OVERVIEW

A committed, innovative and fast-learning Full Stack Web Developer with an extensive experience in leadership and a passion for providing solutions and enhancing customer experience. My 15+ experience in meeting and exceeding business/ customer service goals lead me to find my new passion for web development where I deliver clean and responsive web applications. Passion for working with others and work well under pressure.

CORE COMPETENCIES

LANGUAGES

- JavaScript Ruby SQL
- HTML5 CSS3

LIBRARIES / FRAMEWORKS

- Node.js/Express React
- jQuery Redux Ajax Bootstrap
- Rails EJS/ERB MongoDB
- Sinatra Socket.io
- Visual Studio NPM
- Mocha/Chai Firebase

CONTROL / DEPLOYEMENT

• Git • Github • Heroku

EDUCATION & TRAINING

General Assembly - New York, NY

 WDI - Web Development Immerse -Certificate Of Completion • Achieved 650 hours of full stack application development.

Queensborough Community College - Bayside, NY

Associates Degree - Computer Science

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Serious Fun After School Inc.

New York, NY

Full Stack Developer

10/2017 - current

- Consolidating various third party services into a single custom CMS built with React, Express and Mongo.
- Working Closely with UX design team to improve user experience and providing feedback to improve their design.
- Setting up various Endpoints to provide CMS capabilities.
- Following MVC architectural pattern.

General Assembly - New York, NY

June-2017 - Sep 2017

Web Development Immersive Student

- Photographer's Professional Site Photographer's Dream come true (https://ericsapp.herokuapp.com/) React, Ruby on Rails, Firebase, JS
- App On My Feet: Full Stack Web App Runner's Data Management (https://app-on-my-feet.herokuapp.com//) React, Ruby on Rails, HTML Geolocations, PSQL
- Code Share: Full Stack Web App Bringing individuals together and code (mysterious-anchorage-20913.herokuapp.com/) - React, socket.io, PSQL, Node
- **Tic Tac Toe**: Web Game inspired by Vanilla JS (bitballoon.com/sites/magistrate-peggy-55571) JS, HTML, CSS
- **Ping Pong**: Web Game inspired by Collision Detections using Jquery (asher978.github.io/Project-1-GA) Jquery, HTML, CSS

Armani Exchange | Long Island Area | NY Area Sales Manager

Sep 2005 - Feb 2015

- Growth of 7% increase in sales volume resulting in \$58 million for the Fiscal year 2014
- Led 4 stores within the NYC metro area which included over 200 employees.
- Restructured teams based on talent to allow managers to be more effective at servicing clients.
- Developed and implemented a brand new sales training course resulting in internal growth of managers.
- Pioneered new company initiative KRONOS and provided peer support amongst other stores.